Register of the Nigerian Subject Collection, 1929-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
Nigerian Subject Collection,
1929-2003
XX787
23 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 8 phonorecords, 2 phonotape cassettes, 1 videtape cassette (10.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, serial issues, reports, government documents, flyers, press briefings, and other printed matter, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Nigeria, and to the Nigerian Civil War of 1967-1970.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Nigeria--History--Civil War, 1967-1970.; Nigeria.; Africa.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Video tapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1929-1995. (Boxes 1-9.)
  Booklets, brochures, bulletins, flyers, government documents, leaflets, pamphlets, press briefings, printed matter, reports and serial issues relating to economic, cultural, political and social conditions in Nigeria
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, n.d. (Box 9.)
  Miscellaneous items relating to Nigeria
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1929-1991. (Box 10.)
  Brochures, magazines and press comments relating to various aspects of life in Nigeria
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1976-1986. (Record cabinet; Cassette cabinet; Tape cabinet)
  8 phonorecords, 2 phonotape cassettes and 1 videotape cassette cabinet
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after February 1995
- SUBJECT FILE, 1929-1995
  - General (Box 1)
  - Agriculture
    - General
    - Anambra State
    - Bauchi State
    - Drought
    - Niger State
    - Ondo State
    - Sokoto State
  - Communication (Box 2)
  - Culture
    - General
    - Anikulapo-Kuti, Fela
  - Economics
    - General
    - Budgeting
    - Business
    - Commerce and industry (Box 3)
    - Development Outlook
    - Investment
    - Labor
    - Nigerian Economic Society
    - Sokoto State
    - Trade unions
  - Education
    - General
    - Bayero University
    - Bendel State University
    - Lincoln University
    - National Institute for policy and strategic studies, Kuru (Box 4)
    - Nigerian Institute of Social and Economic Research
    - Obafemi Awolowo University. Includes report of students' clash of 27 May 1991
    - University of Benin Branch
    - University of Calabar
    - University of Cross River State
    - University of Ibadan
    - University of Ife
    - University of Ilorin
    - University of Lagos
    - University of Lagos Women's Society
    - University of Maiduguri
    - University of Nigeria
  - Elections
  - Environment
  - Foreign relations
    - General
    - International law and the International Court of Justice
    - Israel
    - United States
  - Health
    - Human
      - General
      - Acquired Immune Deficiency System (AIDS)
      - Drug abuse
    - Veterinary (Box 5)
  - History
    - General
    - Benue State
    - Civil war, 1966-1970
    - Kaduna State
    - Kano State
    - Katsina State
    - Lagos State
  - Human rights
    - General
    - Civil Liberies Organization (CLO)
    - Committee for the Defence of Human Rights (CDHR)
  - Justice and the judicial system
  - International Support Groups. Amnesty International
  - Military. Includes Dr. M.O. Maduagwu's paper "The Military and the Survival of Democracy in Nigeria," Stanford University, 21 October 1992
  - Pan Africanism
  - Politics and government
    - General
    - General. Includes biography of General Murtala Muhammed (Box 6)
    - Abia State
    - Akwa Ibom State
    - Anambra State
    - Bauchi State (Box 7)
    - Bendel State
    - Benue State
    - Biafra State
    - Borno State
    - Civil service
    - Constitution
    - Cross River State
    - Edo State
    - Enugu State
    - Gongola State
    - Imo State
    - Jigawa State
    - Kaduna State
    - Kano State
    - Katsina State (Box 8)
    - Kogi State
    - Kwara State
    - Lagos State
    - Ministerial Press Briefing
    - Miscellaneous
    - Niger State
    - Offical Gazette
    - Ogoni State
    - Ogun State
    - Oguta State
    - Ondo State
    - Opposition - Campaign for Democracy (CD)
    - Osun State
    - Plateau State
    - Sokoto State
    - Taraba State
  - Political, social and economic organizations
    - Association of Nigerians Abroad (ANA)
    - National Comittee Against Apartheid
    - Nigerian American Association of California
  - Political parties
    - General
    - Great Nigeria People's Party (Box 9)
    - National Party of Nigeria
    - Social Democratic Party
    - Unity Party of Nigeria (UPN)
  - Religion and ethics
    - General
    - Christianity
    - Indigenous
    - Islam
  - Women
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, n.d.
  - Button (Box 9)
  - Invitation
  - Sticker
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1929-1991
  - Brochure, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Magazines, 1990-1991
  - Press comments, native unrest in Calabar and Owerri provinces
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1976-1986
  - Phonorecords (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
    - Anikulapo-Kuti, Fela
      - "Army Arrangement," 1985
      - "Black President," 1984
      - "Kalakuta Show," 1976
      - "No Agreement," 1985
      - "Original Sufferhead," n.d.
      - "Shuffering and Shmiling," 1985
      - "Zombie," 1985
    - "The Pledge and Nigerian National Anthem," n.d.
  - Phonotape cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
    - "International Thief," Fela Anikulapo-Kuti, n.d.
    - "Positive People: One Nation-One Nigeria," n.d.
  - Videocassette tape. "The Nigerian-Biafran War," 1986. Part One (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 11-24:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.